Golnaz Ijadi

⁴ golnaz.ijadi@gmail.com ☎ 07947106860 www.linkedin.com/in/golnazijadi

Summary

With over 7 years of experience as a data scientist and consultant, I have developed a unique skill set in machine learning, data mining and statistical analysis, enabling me to solve complex data problems in energy, health, and finance sectors. I am also proficient in project management and product development for government and private organisations with an experience of working in companies like PwC, ARUP and BRE.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

2017 – 2019 MSc in Computer Science (Distinction), Queen Mary University of London, UK

2009 – 2010 MSc in Management (First class), University of Surrey, UK

2000 – 2004 BSc in Computer Engineering (GPA of 3.27), Qazvin Azad University (QIAU), Iran

KEY SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, SQL, C++, Alteryx **Platforms:** Azure Microsoft, Databricks

Database: SQL Server Management Studio, *Data Bricks*, Oracle **Machine Learning (ML) Algorithms:** Random Forest, XGboost, Lass and Ridge, Decision Tree,

K-NN, CNN

Data Mining and Visualization Tools: Python (Matplotlib), PowerBI, Matlab, Tableau

Statistical data analysis: Python(NumPy, pandas, SciPy), scikit-learn, SPSS, Matlab,

Excel

Project Management Methodology and Tools: PRINCE 2, Microsoft (Project, Excel)

Prediction Tools: PLEXOS, Google Cloud LLM

GenAI tools: Google, LLM, PaLM

EXPERIENCE

Sep 2022 – Present Senior Consultant Data & Analytic, PwC, UK

As a member of the Data & Analytics Team, I drive Enterprise Transformation services, specializing in data analytics, strategy projects, and data function development. With expertise in Capital Projects, Technology, Energy, and Government sectors, I provide expert consulting to enhance organizations' data capabilities. My focus is on delivering high-quality solutions that enable clients to leverage data for business growth. Notable projects include:

- Developed an NLP-powered advanced text application (semantic, keyword, search, entity recognition):
 - Responsible for software development (Python) and client pilots.
- Supported Senior data engineers and project leads as a data analyst:
 - Contributed to solution architecture and data modeling.
- Conducted data gap analysis and maturity assessment as a data analyst:
 - Evaluated data availability, ownership, quality, and accessibility.
 - Identified opportunities for centralizing data, automating reporting, and enhancing efficiency.
- Collaborated with Finance and Regulation teams to integrate and embed data activities.
- Delivered high-quality market analysis as a data scientist:
 - Updated Azure-based big data platform using Data Bricks and Python programming.
 - Developed a customer segmentation analysis framework using Python.

Feb 2020 – Aug 2022 Consultant Data Analyst, ARUP, UK

I was a member of Energy Advisory Team providing Commercial & Market due diligence to investors and strategic players looking at energy facing infrastructure and systems. My main role as data analyst within Investor Advisory team was for the Power Market Analysis (Power system, Trading, and Investment activities) in the UK and overseas.

• Client: North London Waste Authority (NLWA)

NLWA assessed and managed the waste collections performance across 7 local authorities. The role was involved to liaise with the client's organisation and the stakeholders who had multiple roles. I could heavily utilise my technical skills in using database management and analysis.

Role:

Extracted data from the existing database, built a new big data platform using PowerBI.

Client: Gas Distribution Network

As a data analyst, I assessed the revenues from incentivised outputs and how they impacted on the future revenues based on the new regulatory schemes as a part of technical and commercial due diligence for the client.

Achievements:

The analysis results in better client's decision-making process to sell some of their assets.

• Client: Network Rail, Anglia Route

As a data analyst, I reviewed and analysed the Key Performance Indicator data (using Python) from Network Rail, Anglia route, recognising the network performance against the target. We commissioned to develop Strategic Route Asset Management plan. This structured approach provides a clear line of sight between organisational objectives and activity and follows the acknowledged best practice approach to the systematic management of infrastructure.

Achievements:

New maintenance strategy is developed and reported by Arup to the client.

• Client: Poland Electricity Market Research

As a data analyst, using Python (Data mining/cleaning purposes) and PLEXOS Prediction software platform, I provided the forecast for the electricity generation, demand, and supply data for the Polish Electricity Market.

Achievements:

The report assisted the potential investors for the investment opportunities and attracted more client for Arup. Arup provided Electricity Market Report to the client.

• Client: Battery Storage Market Study, StorTera

ARUP commissioned to assess the revenue and costs for the client's battery unit. I supported to update and develop a financial model to support the client identifying potential revenue streams from providing ancillary services using excel financial modelling. Also, I used Customer Value Proposition (CVP) analysis techniques.

Achievements:

The results fed into the cash flow financial model creating Storage as a Service (SaaS) model for the client's financial projections.

• Client: Electricity Distribution Network, SSEN

As a data analyst, I studied low carbon technologies data (Electric Vehicle charging, Distributed generation, heat pumps and electric heat) using data mining techniques and Python.

Achievements:

Development of the uncertainty mechanisms for load-related strategic investment for low carbon technologies.

Jan 2019- Sep 2019 Data Scientist, Voltaware, UK

As a member of the Data Science team, I developed forecasting models for residential power disaggregated data of the household individual appliances. I used Python and several machine learning approaches (including XGboost).

Achievements:

The results led to change of the consumer's behaviour reducing, and improvement of the energy efficiency for the clients.

Mar 2018 – Aug 2019 Consultant Data Analyst, Building Research Establishment (BRE), UK

As a member of the Housing & Health team, I provided the Local Authorities in the UK with periodic reviews of housing stock condition in their areas.

Roles:

Developed predictive Machine Learning algorithms and Logistic Regression method for improving the prediction accuracy rate of the housing stock.

Developed a tenure modelling dataset for commercial corporate ownership database (CCOD) project using Python to reduce the cost of housing stock models purchased from Experian.

Manipulated Data for the BRE housing stock models using SPSS, Excel and Python and ad-hoc big data integration using different data sources including Ordnance Survey, Experian, Energy Performance Certificate, Benefits, Tenancy Deposit Scheme, electoral roll, council tax records, registered social landlords, Households in Multiple Occupation.

Involved in regular maintenance and updated the database using SQL Server Management Studio.

Worked with different business functions, e.g., Marketing, Product, Commercial, Market Research.

Achievements:

Improved the prediction accuracy rate of the housing stock by 30%.

Jul 2016-Jul 2017 Project Coordinator, Surrey County Council, UK

I was a member of the Programme Office where managers and officers worked on high-profile area-wide programmes and projects for the Children, Schools, and Families (CSF) Directorate.

Roles:

Supported Project Managers in establishing the governance standard for their project, ensuring that all controls, and processes are in place.

Ensured that project management documentation including project plans, management reporting, risk, issue and change logs are created and maintained to appropriate standards (Excel, Microsoft Project).

Engaged key stakeholders in updating project objectives to facilitate project delivery.

Achievements:

Improved reporting, updating, project status and reduction of overall project cost by 50% by integrated all individual projects into one centralized program using Microsoft Project.

Apr 2015 - Jul 2016 Data Administrator, Nestle Avenue Children Centre, Hillingdon Council, UK

I was involved in day to day the centre's performance by reviewing the data. The Children's Centre offered early years day care and education provision for children aged 6 months to 5 years.

Achievements:

Improved the engagement and quality of service to the vulnerable families by 80% using data visualization, data analysis, reporting, and client relationships.

Jun 2014 - Jan 2015 Project Support Administrator, Viridian Housing, London, UK,

Supported Project Managers developing the programs across the firm.

2010 – 2013 Delivery Partnership, Personal Assistant, London, UK

Office management and Secretarial role

2004 – 2008 Computer Network Administrator – Pardis Tech Co, Tehran, Iran

I was responsible for the day-to-day operation of the computer networks. I organized, installed, and support an organization's computer systems, including local area networks (LANs), wide area networks (WANs), network segments, intranets, and other data communication systems.